heritageonline.com.au 2015-10-16

# Privacy Policy

## People First is the way we do business

At Heritage, we do things a little differently to the big banks. For starters, we’re owned by customers, not shareholders, so our focus is always on putting ‘ _People first_ ’ by providing customer benefits – in the form of better rates and better service - rather than maximising profits. In everything we do, we put ‘ _People first’._

## Privacy background

Heritage Bank Limited ABN 32 087 652 024, Australian Financial Services Licence and Australian Credit Licence 240984 (also referred to as “Heritage”, “we”, “our” or “us” in this Privacy Policy) considers the protection and maintenance of your personal information to be of the utmost importance. We take very seriously the ongoing trust that you place in us to protect your personal information.

When handling your personal information we are bound and committed to complying with the Australian Privacy Principles in the _Privacy Act 1988_. We are also bound by Division 3 of Part IIIA of the Privacy Act and the Credit Reporting Privacy Code (CR Code), which regulates the handling of credit information, credit eligibility information and related information by credit providers, like us and credit reporting bodies (CRBs) like Veda Advantage Limited, Dun & Bradstreet (Australia) Pty Ltd and Experian Australia Pty Ltd.

This Privacy Policy outlines how we deal with your personal information (including credit-related information), as well as our legal obligations and rights as to that information. If we agree with you to use or disclose any of your personal information in ways which differ to those stated in this Privacy Policy, the provisions of that agreement will prevail to the extent of any inconsistency.

## What does "personal information" mean?

Personal information is information that may identify you or by which your identity may be reasonably determined. The types of personal information that Heritage collects and holds includes the following information about customers, potential customers, and associated persons (such as guarantors) which is relevant to our relationship with that person. Such information may include an individual's name, address, other contact details, date of birth, financial details such as income, savings and lending history and expenses, credit reports from CRBs, employment details, tax file number and the reason a person might be applying for a financial product from us.

## What does "credit eligibility information" mean?

"Credit eligibility information" means information that has been obtained from a CRB (e.g. a consumer credit report), or personal information that has been derived from that information, that is about an individual's consumer credit worthiness.

The kind of information we might derive from an individual's consumer credit report includes:

  * a credit assessment relating to the individual;
  * an unsuitability assessment relating to the individual; and
  * any internal credit scores. 

## What does "credit information" mean?

"Credit information" includes identification information, consumer credit liability information, repayment history information, credit enquiry, type of credit sought, default information, court proceedings and personal insolvency information, publicly available information that relates to the individual’s credit worthiness and information about a serious credit infringement.

We will hold all of this information about an applicant for credit, a guarantor, or related person (for example, a director of a company which has applied for credit).

## Why do we collect your personal information?

We will only ask for personal information (including credit information and credit eligibility information) relevant to our business relationship with you.

We will tell you why we are asking for your personal information when we seek it from you. If you do not provide some personal information, we may not be able to provide you with the products or services you want.

We will seek personal information from you:

  * to check your eligibility for or to provide you or some related person (for example, a person you are acting as guarantor for, or a company you are a director of) with financial products or services; 
  * (unless you ask us not to) to send you information about, products or services offered by Heritage or those provided by third parties that may be of interest to you;
  * to assist you with your enquiries or concerns;
  * to verify your identity and undertake customer due diligence; 
  * for research, training, product development, risk assessment, risk modelling and marketing requirements; and 
  * for any other purpose required or authorised by law.

If you have a credit facility with us or are a guarantor we may also collect your information for the purpose of collecting overdue payments relating to credit you owe or a guarantee you have given and for our internal management purposes related to credit provided.

We may also ask for your personal information because we are obliged to collect it under the _Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorism Financing Act 2006_ , which requires us to ask you for information to check your identity (for instance, by referring to your driver’s licence, birth certificate or passport). 

The _National Consumer Credit Protection Act 2009_ also requires us to make reasonable enquiries when you apply for credit or a credit limit increase. 

Finally, we may collect your TFN in order to calculate our withholding obligations as authorised by the _Taxation Administration Act 1953_ and the _Income Tax Assessment Act 1936_. You are not required to provide your TFN, however if you do not, we may be required to withhold amounts from you and remit them to the Australian Taxation Office.

## How do we collect your personal information

We collect most personal information directly from you. We may do this when you apply for membership, complete an application for one of our products and services, deal with us over the telephone, send us a letter, visit our web site or when you visit our branches (including community and mini branches) or if we call you.

From time to time there may also be occasions (such as where we need to verify your identity, undertake customer due diligence, prevent or detect money laundering or terrorist financing and where we are required or authorised by law) when we need to obtain personal information (including credit information and credit eligibility information) about you from a third party. These parties may include banks, financial advisers, family members, your employer, CRBs, government authorities and publicly available sources of information.

When you ring Heritage (or if Heritage rings you), we may also monitor and/or record telephone calls for the purpose of staff training, to verify statements made during the phone call and to assist with our dispute resolution process.

Our website and Heritage on-line internet banking do not use cookies to identify or monitor visitors to the site.

We do not generally collect sensitive information and if we do, we will only collect sensitive information with your consent.

## How do we store your personal information?

We store your personal information (including credit information and credit eligibility information) in a number of ways including:

  * in computer systems or databases;
  * in hard copy or paper files; and
  * in telephone recordings.

See our comments below about how we protect your information.

## Do we ever disclose your personal information to third parties?

We may disclose your personal information (including credit information and credit eligibility information) to third parties where they help us with our business, or you request us or consent to do so. Where your personal information is disclosed to third parties, we will seek to ensure that the information is held, used or disclosed consistently with the Australian Privacy Principles in Part IIIA of the _Privacy Act 1988 and the CR Code_.

Types of third parties include:

  * parties involved in providing, managing or administering your products or services such as third party suppliers, printers, bulk mail services, statement production providers, authorised representatives and our legal, tax, audit and accountancy advisers; 
  * parties maintaining, reviewing and developing our business systems, procedures and infrastructure including testing or upgrading our computer systems; 
  * alliance partners, for example, where you have a cobranded product such as the Heritage Visa credit card; 
  * advisers or agents which may include lawyers, mortgage brokers, real estate agents, financial advisers, insurance companies, executors, administrators, trustees or attorneys; 
  * CRBs, debt collecting agencies, your guarantors, organisations involved in valuing, surveying, insuring or registering a security property; 
  * lenders mortgage insurers (if insurance is required because the amount you borrow exceeds a certain percentage of the property’s value as insured by Heritage);
  * parties involved in what is known as “securitisation”, under which we sell a pool of home loans. These third parties include trustees of securitisation arrangements, lenders mortgage insurers, investors and their advisers; 
  * other financial institutions, merchants and payment organisations; and
  * the Financial Ombudsman Service and the Superannuation Complaints Tribunal.

We may also disclose your personal information (including credit information and credit eligibility information) to third parties in circumstances where:

  * we must fulfil our legal obligations (for example, disclosure to Australian (and international) enforcement bodies such as the Australian Securities and Investments Commission (ASIC), the Australian Taxation Office (ATO), the Australian Transaction Reports and Analysis Centre (AUSTRAC), Centrelink or the Courts); 
  * it is in the public interest (that is, to protect our interests or where we have a duty to the public to disclose, or where it is necessary in proceedings before a court or tribunal) and where a crime or fraud is committed or is suspected; or 
  * it can be reasonably inferred from the circumstances that you consent to your personal information being disclosed to a third party.

We may also send your personal information outside Australia where, for example:

  * you have requested or consented that we send your personal information; 
  * we outsource a function or service to an overseas contractor with whom we have a contractual arrangement; and 
  * it is necessary to investigate or facilitate a transaction on your behalf.

We will not send your personal information outside Australia unless it is authorised by law and we are satisfied that the recipient of the personal information has adequate data protection arrangements in place. 

The countries to which we are likely to disclose your personal information include New Zealand, Singapore, India, China, United Kingdom, France and the United States of America.

## How do we protect your personal information?

We take all reasonable precautions to protect your personal information, whether it is stored in hard copy or electronic form from loss, unauthorised access, modification and unauthorised disclosure. Your personal information is only accessible by you and by those who are authorised to access it. Our employees and third parties who we deal with are bound by confidentiality obligations.

Hard copy documents are secured on our premises and at archive sites by locks and security systems. Whenever possible, hard copy documents are returned to you and not kept on our premises.

Electronic data is protected by up-to-date computer and network security systems with appropriate firewalls, encryption technology, virus software and access passwords.

We also seek to ensure that confidential face-to-face discussions between you and us occur in a secure environment.

Depending on any legal obligations to retain your personal information for a certain period of time, if we do not require your personal information, we will take reasonable steps to destroy it in a secure manner or by removing identifying features from it.

## Is the Heritage website and Heritage on-line secure?

We appreciate that you may have concerns in relation to the confidentiality and security of your personal information on the internet. Therefore, we have implemented systems to ensure that your personal information is secure and confidential when you access our website or Heritage on-line internet banking.

When we collect your personal information over the internet, it proceeds via our secure server utilising encryption technology. This helps to protect against unauthorised access to your personal information over the Internet. Your stored personal information is also protected from unauthorised access through the use of multiple firewalls, secure passwords and sign-in processes. Further information about the security systems we employ to protect your personal information is available at [www.heritage.com.au](http://www.heritage.com.au/).

While our website and Heritage on-line internet banking rely on the highest levels of technology to ensure maximum security, no data transmission over the internet can be guaranteed to be totally secure.

To assist us in protecting your personal information, we expect you to keep confidential your access passwords at all times, to destroy any documentation we send to you containing your access passwords and to ensure that you log out properly when you leave your computer and take appropriate steps to ensure security of your information.

## How can you access, update or correct your personal information?

We maintain the quality of your personal information by taking reasonable steps to ensure that the information collected, used and disclosed is accurate, complete and up-to-date.

You may request access to your personal information (including credit information and credit eligibility information) at any time by visiting any of our branches, by telephoning our Privacy Officer on 13 14 22, by emailing [feedback@heritage.com.au](mailto:feedback@heritage.com.au) or on-line at [www.heritage.com.au](http://www.heritage.com.au/). We may require you to establish your identity prior to providing you with access to your information. In most cases, we will provide you with access to your information. However, there are some circumstances where we may not give you particular information set out in the _Privacy Act 1988_ , for example if it would be unlawful to do so. If we don't give you the information, we will give you the reasons why. In the event that you make a request to access personal information that has been archived, we may charge you a fee. The fee will be discussed with you prior to us actioning your request. We are unable to give you access to your personal information if we are prevented by law or if access would reveal personal information of another person.

You may also update your personal information (including credit information and credit eligibility information) at any time by visiting any of our branches, by telephoning our Contact Centre on 13 14 22 or on-line at [www.heritage.com.au](http://www.heritage.com.au/ "Heritage Bank - Corporate Website"). We encourage you to advise us immediately if you change your contact details (such as your phone number or address).

Finally, you may request that we correct any information (including credit information and credit eligibility information) we hold about you by telephoning our Privacy Officer on 13 14 22, by emailing [feedback@heritage.com.au ](mailto:feedback@heritage.com.au)or on-line at [www.heritage.com.au](http://www.heritage.com.au/). 

## Do we ever change our Privacy Policy?

From time to time, we may need to review our Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy at any time and to notify you by posting an updated version on our website at [www.heritage.com.au](http://www.heritage.com.au/ "Heritage Bank - Corporate Website").

## Do you have any complaints, concerns or questions about our Privacy Policy?

If you have any concerns or questions about our Privacy Policy, or the way in which we manage your personal information, including if you think we have breached the Australian Privacy Principles, Part IIIA of the _Privacy Act 1988_ or the CR Code, __ you may contact us by:

You may also obtain further information about privacy (including general privacy information, answers to frequently asked questions and links to the Australian Privacy Principles) on the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner’s website at [www.oaic.gov.au](http://www.oaic.gov.au/). Alternatively, you may write to The Office of the Australian Information Commissioner, GPO Box 5218, Sydney, New South Wales, 2001.

## How will your complaint be handled?

While Heritage resolves as many complaints as possible at Branch or Contact Centre level, complaints regarding privacy are referred directly to Heritage's Privacy Officer. The matter will be investigated by the branch or area involved in the complaint and the Customer Relations Manager, and the outcome of which is communicated to the Privacy Officer.

Staff receiving the complaint may be the contact point with the customer and can assure the customer that Heritage has a process to deal with privacy issues. The complaint will be acknowledged within 5 days of receipt, although we will seek to acknowledge the complaint sooner. The complaint will be investigated and if it cannot be resolved within 21 days, Heritage will inform the customer of the progress to date and let them know how long we expect it will take. Unless there are exceptional circumstances involved in the resolution process, the investigation will be completed within 45 days of receiving the complaint. 

Heritage will acknowledge any specific credit reporting breaches or complaints within 7 days of receipt, although we will seek to acknowledge the breach or complaint sooner. Unless there are exceptional circumstances involved in the resolution process, any investigation will be resolved within 30 days of receiving the complaint.

If we are unable to resolve your complaint to your satisfaction within 45 days, you may be eligible to escalate the complaint to our external dispute resolution service. The period of 45 days may be extended in exceptional circumstances. If you wish to escalate the complaint, please tell us and the referral will be facilitated free of charge. 

Our external dispute resolution service is: 

Financial Ombudsman Service (FOS) GPO Box 3 Melbourne, Victoria, 3001 Ph: 1800 367 287 Fax: 03 9613 6399 Website: www.fos.org.au Email: [info@fos.org.au](mailto:info@fos.org.au)

## General Approach 

Your personal information privacy is important to Heritage. Heritage respects your right to be aware of who has information about you, what they are doing with it and why, and who else they are sharing it with. Heritage has adopted a privacy compliance culture that cements this relationship with you. Its foundation is the _Privacy Act 1988_.

## Collection

Information is collected about you to provide you with the product or service you have selected. Types of information collected and handled include identity and contact details of you and your referees, information about your financial circumstances and history, and products or service preferences you may have. Generally, Heritage collects this from you. On occasions, information about you is obtained from others. This allows Heritage to tailor our products and services to best suit your needs.

## Use and Disclosure

Our use and disclosure of information about you is dictated by the product or service you take up. Heritage will not use or disclose this information for a purpose unrelated to this or outside your reasonable expectations where you have asked Heritage not to do so, except where we need to meet a legal obligation or authority. To provide products and services to you in the most cost effective and efficient way, we may need to utilise the services of others. Should this require Heritage to share information, we will require those persons to respect your right of privacy.

## Quality, Access and Correction

Information about you is integral to decisions Heritage makes about our products and services for you. It is essential that that information is correct. You are encouraged to assist us to ensure this by alerting us to any changes in your particular circumstances. You may also access information we hold about you and draw any inaccuracies to our attention.

## Security

Heritage will safeguard information we handle about you. This includes preventing its misuse or loss both internally and externally.

## Contact Heritage

Should you require more information on the way in which Heritage handles information about you, or should you be concerned about our treatment of this information, please contact us on the details provided below.

## Privacy Act Disclosure

Heritage is committed to the proper handling of personal information provided by you and, as such, we want you to be aware of a number of important matters.

Heritage collects your personal information so that we can establish and administer the financial product or service provided to you (including doing all things necessary to provide that product or service (for example assessing your application, managing your account and paying any interest earned), to identify you for and assist you with inquiries, concerns and complaints you may have, for research, training, product development, risk assessment and risk modelling requirements and to tell you about products and services offered by us and conduct customer satisfaction surveys to improve our products and services.

We may also ask for your personal information because we are obliged to collect it under the _Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorism Financing Act 2006_ , which requires us to ask you for information to check your identity (for instance, by referring to your driver’s licence, birth certificate or passport).

The _National Consumer Credit Protection Act 2009_ also requires us to make reasonable inquiries when you apply for credit or a credit limit increase.

If you do not provide personal information to us, we may not be able to provide a financial product, or we may be required to restrict operation of a financial product.

For you information, we may also collect your TFN in order to calculate our withholding obligations as authorised by the _Taxation Administration Act 1953_ and the _Income Tax Assessment Act 1936_. You are not required to provide your TFN, however if you do not, we may be required to withhold amounts from you and remit them to the Australian Taxation Office.

Where possible, we will collect personal information about you directly from you. From time to time there may also be occasions (such as where we need to verify your identity, undertake customer due diligence, prevent or detect money laundering or terrorist financing and where we are required or authorised by law) when we need to obtain personal information (including credit information and credit eligibility information) about you from a third party. These parties may include banks, financial advisers, family members, your employer, CRBs, government authorities and publicly available sources of information.

If you provide us with information about someone else, you agree to inform that person about the contents of this document as it applies to them.

We may exchange your personal information with third parties in the normal operations of our business, for example with:

  * our corporate partners, alliance partners, related companies and agents;
  * parties involved in providing, managing or administering your products or services such as third party suppliers, printers, bulk mail services, statement production providers, authorised representatives and our legal, tax, audit and accountancy advisers;
  * parties responsible for maintaining, reviewing and developing our business systems, procedures and infrastructure including testing or upgrading our computer systems;
  * your authorised representatives including your legal and financial advisers; and
  * government agencies and service providers (such as printers, bulk mail services, statement production providers, authorised representatives and our legal, tax, audit and accountancy advisers).

We may also send your personal information outside Australia where, for example:

  * you have requested or consented that we send your personal information; 
  * we outsource a function or service to an overseas contractor with whom we have a contractual arrangement; and 
  * it is necessary to investigate or facilitate a transaction on your behalf.

We will not send your personal information outside Australia unless it is authorised by law and we are satisfied that the recipient of the personal information has adequate data protection arrangements in place. 

The countries to which we are likely to disclose your personal information include New Zealand, Singapore, India, China, the UK, France and the US.

When you provide us with personal information, you consent to us:

  * collecting, using and disclosing information about you in the manner described above; and
  * (unless you opt out) using your personal information to identify and provide you with information about products and services you may be interested in.

Heritage's Privacy Policy, a copy of which can be obtained online at [www.heritage.com.au](http://www.heritage.com.au/) contains information about how you can access and correct information we hold about you, how you can complain about a breach by us of your privacy rights and how your complaint will be handled. It also contains a more comprehensive list of countries to which your information may be disclosed and will be updated regularly. 

## Contact us

You may contact our Privacy Officer in relation to your personal information (or to opt out of marketing) on 13 14 22, by email at [feedback@heritage.com.au](mailto:feedback@heritage.com.au) or by writing to the Privacy Officer, Heritage Bank Limited, Reply Paid 190, Toowoomba, Qld, 4350.
